Eugenics Record Office Records 1670-1964 Mss.Ms.Coll.77
American Philosophical Society
- Series VII. Field Worker Files, 1911-1926 (Box Series VII: 1-2)
  - Eaton, A.B., #4, 1911 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Moore, E.P., #7, 1911 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Muncey, E.B., #15, 1912 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Curial, M.T., #23, 1914-1915 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Robinson, V.P., #26, 1913 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Udell, Z.E., #36, 1913 (Box Series VII-1)
  - George, Fannie, #41, 1913 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Thayer, Ethel H., #48, 1917 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Huschka, Mabel C., #57, 1915 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Douglas, Edith M., #64, 1916 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Coyle, Sarah E., #69, 1917 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Pfister, Bertha, #75, n.d. (Box Series VII-1)
  - Giffin, Bertha, #81, 1918 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Bingham, Esther, #88, 1920 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Whittier School, #94, 1922 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Letchworth Village, #95, 1922 (Box Series VII-1)
  - "Meeting of the Field Workers", 23 Jun. 1915 (Box Series VII-1)
  - "Numbers of Eugenics Record Office Field Workers", n.d. (Box Series VII-1)
  - "Research Department. Suggestions", 1915, 1917 (Box Series VII-1)
  - Card File Box, 1911-1926 (Box Series VII-2)
- Series VIII. Volunteer Collaborators, 1912-1939 (Box Series VIII: 1-5)
  Files compiled by 29 volunteer field workers, who did not receive training from the Eugenics Record Office as the other field workers did. The files contain biographical reports, pedigrees, and lineages done by volunteers for families in the locale of each volunteer. The folders are filed numerically by the volunteer number of each person. The files for some volunteers are missing (10, 24, 25, 26). There are also items for which no volunteer numbers were given. These folders have been filed alphabetically after the volunteer numbers and include miscellaneous trait files, a model chart ("Rational or Artificial Selection (Model)"), and baby books and daily logs for members of the Cory family.
  - Dunkley, Mary E., V.C. 1, 1913 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Byrnes, Dr., V.C. 2, 1913 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Monroe, Will S., V.C. 3, 1913-1914 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Johnson, Ralph L., V.C. 4, 1912-1916 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Dow, G.S., V.C. 5, 1914; 2 Folders (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Slaughter, Mildred, V.C. 6, 1914-1915 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Peterson, Anna M., V.C. 7, 1913-1914 (Box Series VIII-1)
  - Gardner, Dorothy B., V.C. 8 (Box Series VIII: 1-2)
    - Folder #1, 1914 (Box Series VIII-1)
    - Folder #2, 1914 (Box Series VIII-2)
    - Folder #3, 1914 (Box Series VIII-2)
    - Folder #4, 1914 (Box Series VIII-2)
    - Folder #5, 1914 (Box Series VIII-2)
    - Folder #6, 1915 (Box Series VIII-2)
    - Folder #7, 1915 (Box Series VIII-2)
    - Folder #8, 1915 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Kirk, Sara K., V.C. 9, 1914, 1916 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Webster, H.B., V.C. 11, 1915 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Mellen, Ida M., V.C. 12, 1912 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Stedman, Edith G., V.C. 13, 1915 (Box Series VIII-2)
  - Reichert, F.L., V.C. 14, 1917-1920 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Reed, Bernice, V.C. 15, 1916 (Box Series VIII-3)
    - Letter from Bernice Reed to C. B. Davenport on studying a "low grade moral family," page 1, 1916 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Myers, Sadie, V.C. 16, n.d. (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Churchill, Edw. D., V.C. 17, 1918 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Klein, Jessie E., V.C. 18, 1918-1919 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Chapin, F.S. (Prof.), V.C. 19, 1920 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Osborn, M., V.C. 20, 1920 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Lloyd, Bess, V.C. 21, 1923 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Mead, Pauline, V.C. 22, 1922 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Wells, A.F., V.C. 23 (Box Series VIII-3)
    - Folder #1, 1923 (Box Series VIII-3)
    - Folder #2, 1924 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Steggerda, Morris, V.C. 27, n.d. (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Fox, Marian, V.C. 28, 1931 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Tassell, Royal R., V.C. 29, 1933-1934 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Allen, William, 1935, 1939 (Box Series VIII-4)
  - Ballentine, Robert, 1935 (Box Series VIII-4)
  - Black - Hunt - Laughlin, 1936 (Box Series VIII-4)
  - Cory, Harry Thomas (Box Series VIII-4)
    - "Ancestry of Thomas Judd Cory, Clarence Richard Cory, John Harry Cory", 17 Jan. 1920; 2 Folders (Box Series VIII-4)
  - Cory, John Harry (Box Series VIII-4)
    - Baby book, 1916-1925 (Box Series VIII-4)
    - Daily log, 1917-1921 (Box Series VIII-4)
  - Cory, Thomas Judd (Box Series VIII: 4-5)
    - Baby book, 1914-1923 (Box Series VIII-4)
    - Daily log, 1915-1919 (Box Series VIII-5)
  - Freeman - Gampp - Burchard - Gibbs, 1937 (Box Series VIII-5)
  - Kindred 14, 1935; 2 Folders (Box Series VIII-5)
  - "Material for Archivist", 1937-1939, n.d. (Box Series VIII-5)
  - Rational or Artifical Selection (Model), n.d. (Box Series VIII-5)
- Series IX. Pedigrees, 1828-1946 (Box Series IX-1)
  Pedigree charts, the majority of which are oversized and in fragile condition. Most charts are detailed pedigrees and/or genealogies of specific families, including such prominent individuals as Abraham Lincoln, Theodore Roosevelt, and J.S. Bach. This series also includes more general materials used in various E.R.O. studies, e.g., a map of Quicksand, Kentucky; and physical development records of infants in Washington, D.C.
  - Document Box (Box Series IX-1)
    - Bowlsby Family, 1942 (Box Series IX-1)
      -See also Oversized
    - Fenske, H.O., n.d. (Box Series IX-1)
    - Mast, Beata and Gottlob, 1828-1946 (Box Series IX-1)
    - Miscellaneous Pedigrees, 1909-1930 (Box Series IX-1)
      - Pedigree of Tribe of Ishmael, n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Pedigree chart. (Box Series IX-1)
    - Sabeans Family--Charts, n.d. (Box Series IX-1)
    - Sabeans Family--Correspondence, 1926 (Box Series IX-1)
    - Saratoga Springs, New York High School, 1940 (Box Series IX-1)
    - Shull Junior High School (Easton, PA), 1943 (Box Series IX-1)
  - Oversized (Os Series IX)
    - Abbott Family, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Bach Family: A Striking Example of Inheritance of Musical Ability, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Bodden Family, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Bowlsby Family Pedigree, 1942 (Os Series IX)
      -See also Document Box
    - Chart of Illick Family, 1928 (Os Series IX)
    - Chart on Sociology--Smith College, V.C. 19, F.S. Chapin, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Clarke Family Tree, 1914 (Os Series IX)
    - de Wessyngton, Robert, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Dissimilar Heredity and Social Effluence of a Pennsylvania Family (Os Series IX)
      - Charts A and B (Os Series IX)
    - Edison, Thomas (Os Series IX)
      - 2 Charts, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Fenske, H.O., n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Growth Records of Infants from Washington, D.C., 3 Charts (Os Series IX)
    - The Hapsburg L[...] Trait in Certain Royal Families Through 500 Years, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Illick Family, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Jeremiah and Susanna LaVollée--Pedigree of Three Traits: Industry, Restraint, and Judgement (Os Series IX)
    - Lincoln, Abraham--Pedigree, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - McCourtie--John and Jeannie McClawcline. Both of Scotland, 1918 (Os Series IX)
    - The Near-Kin of Theodore Roosevelt. Biological Study of Natural Inheritance, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Paternal Ancestry of Clagett Bowie, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Peter Foy-Hamital Moore Pedigree, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Physical Developmental Records for Infants in Washington, D.C. (Os Series IX)
      - 3 Charts, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Quicksand, Kentucky--Map (Os Series IX)
    - Robb, R.C. (Os Series IX)
      - 3 Charts, n.d. (Os Series IX)
    - Shawver and Kirkpatrick Families (Os Series IX)
      - #1-3, 1919 (Os Series IX)
      - #4, 1921 (Os Series IX)
      - #5, 1919 (Os Series IX)
    - Shinnecock Indians Pedigree Chart (Os Series IX)
    - Washington, George, 8 July 1932 (Os Series IX)
    - Whitney Genealogy, 1895 (Os Series IX)
- Series X. Harry H. Laughlin Files, 1915-1938 (Box Series X: 1-6)
  Material that seems to have been collected by Harry H. Laughlin on the topic of blindness. There are two folders of correspondence between Laughlin and Lucien Howe (filed under Laughlin's name) from 1915 to 1928; materials for Howe's Bibliography of Hereditary Eye Defects; statistics gathered about the cost of blindness to the government; responses to questionnaires sent to colleges and universities nationwide about courses being given on eugenics in 1920; general correspondence about eye defects and blindness and about hereditary blindness; manuscripts by Lucien Howe and by Albert Govaerts; Physical Developmental Record charts and correspondence; and responses to questionnaires sent to schools for the blind. This series also includes two card files. One contains information on tuberculosis gathered by A. Govaerts for his "Heredity Factor in the Etiology of Tuberculosis." The only label that survived from a crumbling envelope that contained the other card file indicates that this file holds information about blind and partially blind people.
  - American Eugenics Society, Inc.-- Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box Series X-1)
  - Bibliography of Hereditary Eye Defects--Correspondence, 1918-1928 (Box Series X-1)
  - Bibliography of Hereditary Eye Defects--Research Materials, n.d. (Box Series X-1)
  - Case Studies Regarding Blindness, 1921 (Box Series X-1)
  - Committee on the Prevention of Hereditary Blindness, 1919-1921 (Box Series X-1)
  - Cost of Blindness for Government, 1918-1928, n.d. (Box Series X-1)
  - Definition of Blindness, 1927 (Box Series X-1)
  - "Eugenics"--Broadside, n.d. (Box Series X-1)
    "Eugenics, like a tree, Eugenics draws its materials from many sources"
  - Eugenics Instruction Questionnaires (Box Series X-1)
    - Folder #1, A-Ham, 1920 (Box Series X-1)
    - Folder #2, Har-P, 1920 (Box Series X-1)
    - Folder #3, R-Univ. of Ma, 1920 (Box Series X-1)
      - Zoology Department Course Descriptions, University of Idaho, 1920 (Box Series X-1)
      - Zoology Department Course Descriptions: Heredity and Genetics, Social Hygiene; University of Idaho, 1920 (Box Series X-1)
    - Folder #4, Univ. of Mi-Y, 1920 (Box Series X-1)
  - "Eugenics Militant"--Manuscript, n.d. (Box Series X-1)
  - Eugenics Record Office Brochure, [191-?] (Box Series X-2)
  - Eugenics Research Association, 1927-1928 (Box Series X-2)
  - Eye Defects and Blindness-Batavia School, 1923 (Box Series X-2)
  - Eye Defects and Blindness--Correspondence, 1920-1924 (Box Series X-2)
  - Govaerts, Albert. "Heredity Factor in the Etiology of Tuberculosis", 1922; 5 Folders (Box Series X-2)
    -See also Ser.X, Box #5, Tuberculosis Card File
  - Hereditary Blindness--Correspondence (Box Series X-2)
    - Folder #1, A-Da, 1915-1928 (Box Series X-2)
    - Folder #2, De-W, 1918-1927 (Box Series X-2)
  - Hereditary Blindness--Research Materials (Box Series X-3)
    - Kallikak family pedigree, n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Heredity chart demonstrating inheritance of "feeble-mindedness." (Box Series X-3)
  - Hereditary Blindess Law--Questionnaires (Box Series X-3)
    - Folder #1, A-H, 1921 (Box Series X-3)
    - Folder #2, I-Y, 1921 (Box Series X-3)
  - Hereditary Blindness Law--Research Materials, 1921-1928, n.d. (Box Series X-3)
    Includes pam. of Supreme Court decision on case of Carrie Buck, 1926
  - Howe, Lucien. "Concerning a Law to Lessen Hereditary Blindness", 1926 (Box Series X-3)
  - H.H. Laughlin and Lucien Howe Correspondence (Box Series X-3)
    - Folder #1, 1915-1921 (Box Series X-3)
    - Folder #2, 1922-1928 (Box Series X-3)
  - Physical Developmental Record--Charts, 1925, n.d. (Box Series X-3)
  - Physical Developmental Record--Correspondence (Box Series X: 3-4)
    - Folder #1, A-E, 1924-1933 (Box Series X-3)
    - Folder #2, F-N, 1924-1927 (Box Series X-4)
    - Folder #3, O-T, 1924-1926 (Box Series X-4)
    - Folder #4, U-W, 1924-1926 (Box Series X-4)
  - Questionnaire Responses from Schools for the Blind, 1920; 2 Folders (Box Series X-4)
  - Severs, Tura Groas. [First-Hand Information Concerning Metrasol Treatments], 1938 (Box Series X-4)
  - Tuberculosis Card File, [1922] (Box Series X-5)
  - Blind Persons Card File (Box Series X-6)
- Series XI. Bibliographia Eugenica, 1734-1934 (Box Series XI: 1-21)
  Extensive abstracts, pedigree charts, and annotated bibliographies of European and American medical journal articles that were used in the publication of Bibliographia Eugenica, a supplement to Eugenical News, which was compiled and edited by Mabel Lavinia Earle from 1927 until 1934. According to the Explanatory Note (see folder titled "Rules and Abbreviations Used in Publishing the Bibliography"), the bibliographies were intended to help investigators in the field of eugenics to "keep in touch with what has been published; and to know who are current investigators in the field of their own researches." Folders are filed alphabetically either by clinical condition or by the name of the abstracted article's author. A substantial number of the abstracts (22 folders) concern multiple births. Several files contain correspondence between Earle and Charles B. Davenport or Harry H. Laughlin, which is indicated on the outside of the folder. Also in this series are eight card file boxes that contain abstracts from Volumes I and II of Bibliographia Eugenica. The abstracts were clipped from the volumes, pasted onto file cards, and filed alphabetically by author's name. One card file contains handwritten abstracts and is also filed alphabetically by author's name.
  - Achondroplasia, 1902-1923; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-1)
  - Adiposis Dolorosa, 1906, 1921-1922 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Albinism, 1920, 1923 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Amaurotic Family Idiocy, 1898-1920; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-1)
  - Anaemia, Pernicious, 1900-1926 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Anaemia, Sickle Cell, 1911-1926 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Appendicitis, 1896, 1907 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Asthma and Hay Fever, 1913-1924 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Ataxy (Friedrich's Type, Pierre-Marie Type, Intermediate Forms), 1920-1925 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Author Abstracts--A, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-1)
  - Author Abstracts--Ban-Boy, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-2)
  - Author Abstracts--Bra-Byc, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-2)
  - Author Abstracts--Cal-Cle, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-2)
  - Author Abstracts--Cob-Czy, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-2)
  - Author Abstracts--D, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-2)
  - Author Abstracts--E, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-2)
  - Author Abstracts--F, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-2)
  - Author Abstracts--G, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-3)
  - Author Abstracts--Han-Heu, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-3)
  - Author Abstracts--Hic-Hut, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-3)
  - Author Abstracts--I-J, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-3)
  - Author Abstracts--K, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-3)
  - Author Abstracts--L, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-3)
  - Author Abstracts--M, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-4)
  - Author Abstracts--N-O, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-4)
  - Author Abstracts--P-Q, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-4)
  - Author Abstracts--R, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-4)
  - Author Abstracts--Sa-Sl, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-4)
  - Author Abstracts--Sm-Sy, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-4)
  - Author Abstracts--T-V, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-5)
  - Author Abstracts--W-Z, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-5)
  - Bibliographia Eugenica-- Galley Proofs, 1932 (Box Series XI-5)
  - Bibliographia Eugenica-- Material for Headings, n.d. (Box Series XI-5)
  - Bibliographia Eugenica-- Page Proofs, 1932-1933 (Box Series XI-5)
  - Bibliographia Eugenica-- References, 1933-1934; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-5)
  - Biography--Explorers and Generals, 1880-1916 (Box Series XI-5)
    Contains Davenport correspondence
  - Blood Groups, 1910-1926 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Cancer, 1866-1926 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Castration, 1873-1925 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Cataract, 1907-1926 (Box Series XI-6)
  - "Contents of Trunk in Basement", n.d. (Box Series XI-6)
  - Diabetes, 1864-1926 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Dipsomania, 1905-1921 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Ductless Glands, 1913-1925 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Elliptical Human Erythrocytes, 1914, 1923 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Epidermolysis Bullosa Hereditaria, 1882-1926 (Box Series XI-6)
  - Epilepsy, 1865-1925; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-6)
  - Fingers, Congenital Contraction of, 1905-1933; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-7)
  - Folie à Deux; Folie à Trois, 1920-1924 (Box Series XI-7)
  - Fragilitas Ossium; Blue Sclerotics, 1901-1926; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-7)
  - Haemorrhagic Diathese; Haemorrhagic Thrombasthenie, 1918-1924 (Box Series XI-7)
  - Ichthyosis; Keratosis, 1833-1924; 3 Folders (Box Series XI-7)
  - Jaundice, 1908-1925 (Box Series XI-7)
  - Leukemia, 1880-1925 (Box Series XI-7)
  - Medical Biographies, 1919 (Box Series XI-7)
  - Mental Disease--Dementia Praecox; Schizophrenia, 1920-1925 (Box Series XI-8)
  - Mental Disease, Inheritance of, 1912 (Box Series XI-8)
  - Mental Disease--Manic Depressive Insanity, 1909-1919 (Box Series XI-8)
  - Metacarpals--Short, 1900-1929 (Box Series XI-8)
  - Migraine, 1900-1925 (Box Series XI-8)
  - Mongolism, 1900-1925 (Box Series XI-8)
  - Multiple Births, 1833-1925; 4 Folders (Box Series XI-8)
  - Multiple Births--Bibliography and Abstracts of Articles, 1834-1920 (Box Series XI-9)
  - Multiple Cartilaginous Exostoses, 1880-1925; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-9)
  - Multiple Sclerosis and Allied Troubles, 1880-1920 (Box Series XI-9)
  - Myopia, 1880-1930 (Box Series XI-9)
  - Nephritis; Bright's Disease; Contracted Kidney; Albuminuria; Uraenuria, 1870-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Notebook, n.d. (Box Series XI-10)
  - Notes on Books, 1911-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Notes on Books and Journals, 1910-1926 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Notes on Journals, 1912-1926; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-10)
  - Obesity, 1850-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Optic Atrophy; Leber's Disease, 1900-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Paralysis--General and Various Forms, 1870-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Paralysis--Spastic, 1880-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Periodic Paralysis, 1880-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Polymastia, 1820-1925 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Population, 1918 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Prussian Grenadiers, 1734-1910 (Box Series XI-10)
  - Quadruplets, 1790-1910 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Quintuplets, 1820-1925 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Radio-Ulnar Synostosis; Tibio-Fibular Synostosis, 1870-1925 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Repopulation of France, 1912-1917 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Ringed Hair, 1922 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1919 (Box Series XI-11)
    Contains Earle-Laughlin correspondence
  - Rules and Abbreviations Used in Publishing the Bibliography, [1927] (Box Series XI-11)
  - Splenomegaly; Haemolytic Splenomegaly; Splenic Anaemia, 1900-1925 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Sterilisation, 1900-1925 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Strabismus; Squint; Schielens, 1880-1925 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Suicide, 1885-1925 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Triplets, 1870-1925; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-11)
  - Tuberculosis, 1925 (Box Series XI-11)
  - Twins, 1870-1925; 4 Folders (Box Series XI-12)
  - Twins, Disease in, 1920-1925 (Box Series XI-12)
  - Twins, Inheritance of Pathologic Conditions in, 1919-1926; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-12)
  - Twins, Insanity in, 1883-1919; 2 Folders (Box Series XI-12)
  - Twins and Multiple Births, 1926 (Box Series XI-12)
  - Von Recklinghausen's Disease, 1820-1925; 3 Folders (Box Series XI-13)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, Vol. I; A-E, 1925-1930 (Box Series XI-14)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, Vol. I, F-K, 1925-1930 (Box Series XI-15)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, Vol. I, L-R, 1925-1930 (Box Series XI-16)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, Vol. I, S-Z, 1925-1930 (Box Series XI-17)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, Vol. II, A-G, 1930-1934 (Box Series XI-18)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, Vol. II, H-O, 1930-1934 (Box Series XI-19)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, Vol. II, P-Z, 1930-1934 (Box Series XI-20)
  - Card File: Bibliographia Eugenica, References, 1933-1934 (Box Series XI-21)
- Series XII. Midget Schedules, 1840s-1964 (Box Series XII: 1-2)
  "Midget schedules" from 1934, filed alphabetically by last name. The data was compiled from midgets who were assembled from around the world to work in the "Midget Village" at the World's Fair in Chicago in 1933 and in 1934. The "midget schedules" include measurements and trait descriptions. Also in this series are files of clippings, correspondence, notes, and photographs concerning the Midget Village, including an oversized photograph of the midgets who worked there. There is one card file containing bibliographical citations about midgets, as well as traits for individual midgets.
  - Clippings, 1933-1934, 1938, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
  - Correspondence, 1934, 1938 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Giant--Photographs, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
    -See also Ser.XII, Reichert, Gilbert
  - Midget Village, Chicago, 2 Nov. 1933 (Os Series XII)
    -See Oversized "X." See also Ser.XII, Notes
  - Notes, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Photographs, 1919, 1964, n.d. (Os Series XII)
    -See also Oversized "X," Ser.XII, "Midget Village, Chicago"
    - Midgets at Luna Park, Coney Island, New York., ca. 1919 (Os Series XII)
  - Abner, Anna, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Allison, Gladys, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Antonius, Martha, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Banbury, John, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Ber, Frank, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Bloszek, Olonka, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Botonyr, Susanna, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Bump, Victor, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Burbank, Mary Ellen, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Cantna, L., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
    Folder read "Cantna, Leila"
  - Cooper, Norma Appleby, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - De Pussy, Carmo, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - David, Frederick, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - David, Karl, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Delfino, Frank, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Doss, Lafayette, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Doyle, James, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Duccini, Fred, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Dudek, Frank, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Dudek, Mike, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Edwards, Hollis, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Farkas, Gladys, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Finch, Clarence, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Fish, H., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Frank, Addie, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Gesper, Steve, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Glicken, J., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Goodrow, Fred, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Gorna, Carolina, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Gorna, Helena, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Hendry, Jean, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Herbst, Joseph, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Holgate, R., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Hoy, Helen, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Hoy, Marguerite, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Keel, W., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Keenan, Thomas J., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Keesar, C.L., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Kelley, Charles, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Kelley, Jessie Chappell, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Kikel, Frank, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - King, Edith, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Koestner, Emma, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Koestner, Mitzi, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Koestner, Willie, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Kowalski, Robert, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Kozicka, Adam, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Krueger, Werner, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Laible, Ann, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Laible, George, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Leonard, Bernice, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Ludwig, Charles, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Ludwig, Elizabeth Hoy, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
  - Matina, Ike, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Matina, Mike, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Mayr, J., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Ministeri, George, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Montague, Daniel, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Newman, J., 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
    Folder read "Newman, Jeannette"
  - Nickloy, Margaret, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Packard, Frank, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Page, Nick, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Palfi, Jean, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Porter, Lillian, 1934 (Box Series XII-1)